Guide to the Stewart M. Brandborg Papers 1932-2000
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- The Wilderness Society, 1930-1977; Series IV; 28.0 linear ft.
  - Subject Files, 1930-1977; Subseries 2; 25.75 linear ft.
    - Wilderness Hearings, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 67/8)
    - Wilderness Issues, Correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 67/9)
    - Wilderness Law Change, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 67/10)
    - Wilderness Management Plans, 1974 (Box-folder 67/11-12)
    - Wilderness Management Policy, 1974 (Box-folder 67/13)
    - Wilderness Plan for Everglades National Park, 1968 (Box-folder 67/14)
    - Wilderness Prospecting, undated (Box-folder 67/15)
    - Wilderness Public Hearings, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 67/16)
    - Wilderness Report, 1975 (Box-folder 67/17)
    - Wilderness Report Notes, 1972 (Box-folder 67/18)
    - Wilderness Report Plan, undated (Box-folder 67/19)
    - Wilderness Reviews Correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 68/1)
    - Wilderness Society and Sierra Club Joint Staff Meeting, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 68/2)
    - Wilderness Society Logo Plan, 1975 (Box-folder 68/3)
    - Wilderness Society Records, Denver Conservation Library, 1969 (Box-folder 68/4)
    - Wilderness Society Regions, undated (Box-folder 68/5)
    - Wilderness Strategy Meeting, Sierra Club, San Francisco, 1973 (Box-folder 68/6)
    - Wilderness Study Institute, University of Montana, Reports and Studies, 1974 (Box-folder 68/7)
    - Wilderness Trip Court Cases, 1969 (Box-folder 68/8)
    - Wilderness User Studies, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 68/9)
    - Wildernesses Trip Plans, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 68/10)
    - Wildlife, 1973 (Box-folder 68/11)
    - Wildlife and Habitat Coordinating Committee, 1974 (Box-folder 68/12)
    - Wildlife and Habitat Coordinating Committee, 1974 (Box-folder 68/13)
    - Wildlife Conference and Meeting Brochures, 1961-1966 (Box-folder 68/14)
    - Wildlife Management Institute, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 68/15)
    - Wildlife Management Institute, C.R. Gutermuth Statements, 1969 (Box-folder 68/16)
    - Wildlife Range Transfer, 1975 (Box-folder 68/17)
    - Wildlife Refuge Transfer to Bureau of Land Management Correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 68/18)
    - Wildlife Society, 1969 (Box-folder 68/19)
    - Williams Law Dinner, 10th Anniversary, 1974 (Box-folder 68/20)
    - R.T. Williams, Biographical File, 1974 (Box-folder 68/21)
    - Wingspread Conference, 1975 (Box-folder 68/22)
    - Wyoming Conservation Meetings, 1971 (Box-folder 68/23)
    - Yamagoda Priorities, 1974 (Box-folder 68/24)
    - Yellowstone National Park Centennial Speech, 1972 (Box-folder 68/25)
    - Yosemite Workshop, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 68/26)
    - Youth Plans, Workshops, Student Groups, Mailing Lists, 1970 (Box-folder 68/27)
    - Howard Zahniser Memorial Wilderness Collection, 1970 (Box-folder 68/28)
- Citizens Action Center, 1976-1977; Series V; 0.5 linear ft.
  This series consists of subject files primarily containing correspondence, plan proposals, and notes.
  - Billing, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 68/29)
  - Plans Proposal, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 68/30)
  - Proposal, 1976 (Box-folder 68/31)
  - Conservation Workshop Manual, 1976 (Box-folder 69/1-2)
  - In the Middle Newsletter, 1976 (Box-folder 69/3)
  - Pacific Northwest Conservation Council, 1976 (Box-folder 69/4)
- National Park Service, 1976-1982; Series VI; 4.5 linear ft.
  This series contains information regarding the development and implementation of The National Park Service citizen participation program, including notes, internal memos and correspondence, budgetary planning materials, and work plans. Subject Files include correspondence, meeting notes, and training materials.
  - Administration, 1976-1981; Subseries 1; 3.25 linear ft.
    - Blue Ridge Conference Notes and Planning, 1979 (Box-folder 69/5)
    - Citizen Involvement and Public Participation Strategy and Handbooks, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 69/6)
    - Citizen Leader Proposal, undated (Box-folder 69/7)
    - Citizen Participation Action Plan, 1979 (Box-folder 69/8)
    - Citizen Participation Briefing, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 69/9)
    - Citizen Participation Conference Costs, 1980 (Box-folder 69/10)
    - Citizen Participation Consultant and Training Services, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 69/11)
    - Citizen Participation Consultant File, 1980 (Box-folder 69/12)
    - Citizen Participation Documentation, Stewart M. Brandborg, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 69/13)
    - Citizen Participation Plans Advisory Group, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 69/14)
    - Citizen Participation Position, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 70/1-2)
    - Citizen Participation Presentation, Assistant Secretary Meeting, undated (Box-folder 70/3)
    - Citizen Participation Program, 1978 (Box-folder 70/4)
    - Citizen Participation Program Inventory Form, undated (Box-folder 70/5)
    - Citizen Participation Program, Participatory Design, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 70/6)
    - Citizen Participation Program Plan, 1978 (Box-folder 70/7)
    - Citizen Participation Program Plan, Comments by National Park Service, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 70/8)
    - Citizen Participation Program Plan, Departmental Manual, undated (Box-folder 70/9)
    - Citizen Participation Program, Program Prospectus, 1978 (Box-folder 70/10)
    - Citizen Participation Program, Leadership Conference Materials, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 70/11)
    - Citizen Participation Program, Long-Term Management Plan, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 71/1-2)
    - Citizen Participation Program, Management Report Process, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 71/3)
    - Citizen Participation Program, Memos-Planning, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 71/4)
    - Citizen Participation Program, Work Evaluation, 1980 (Box-folder 71/5)
    - Citizen Participation Programs, Southeast Regional Office, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 71/6)
    - Citizen Participation Work Plan for Regional Directors and Superintendants, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 71/7)
    - Citizen Participation, Department of the Interior Actions, 1977 (Box-folder 71/8)
    - Citizen Participation, Director's Memo, 1979 (Box-folder 71/9)
    - Citizen Training Program Guidelines, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 71/10-11)
    - Consumer/Citizen Participation Program, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 72/1)
    - Controlled Decision Process Tracking System, Issues Lists, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 72/2)
    - Correspondence to Directorate, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 72/3-4)
    - Denver Support Center, Citizen Participation, 1977 (Box-folder 72/5)
    - Development of the National Park Service Citizen Participation Program, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 72/6-7)
    - Environmental Planning Session, 1977 (Box-folder 72/8-9)
    - Executive Committee Training Materials, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 72/10)
    - Executive Order for Citizen Participation, 1980 (Box-folder 73/1)
    - Expense Claims, Miscellaneous, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 73/2)
    - Follow-up Planning on Valley Forge Conference, 1979 (Box-folder 73/3)
    - Group Task Roles, 1980 (Box-folder 73/4)
    - Harper's Ferry Retreat, National Park Service, 1980 (Box-folder 73/5)
    - Interagency Regional Meeting Proposal, 1977 (Box-folder 73/6)
    - Interdepartmental Coordination for Public Participation Process, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 73/7)
    - Interior Department Citizen Participation Planning/Training, 1980 (Box-folder 73/8)
    - Memos, Citizen Participation Program, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 73/9)
    - Memos, Department of the Interior, 1978 (Box-folder 73/10)
    - Mid-Atlantic Regional Office, Citizen Participation Plans for Parks, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 73/11)
    - National Parks Conservation Association, Citizen Involvement Program, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 74/1)
    - New England Regional Conference Plans, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 74/2)
    - Position Descriptions, Citizen Participation Program, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 74/3)
    - Preliminary Work Plan, 1977 (Box-folder 74/4)
    - Program Plans, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 74/5-6)
    - Program Prospectus, National Park Service Citizen Participation Program, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 74/7)
    - Public Involvement Guidelines, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 74/8-9)
    - Public Involvement in Planning, 1978 (Box-folder 75/1)
    - Public Involvement, Citizen Participation, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 75/2-3)
    - Southeastern Regional Office, Citizen Participation Inventory, 1977 (Box-folder 75/4)
    - Southeastern Regional Office, Regional Group Plans, 1979 (Box-folder 75/5)
    - Travel File, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 75/6)
    - Washington Support Office Citizen Participation Steering Group, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 75/7)
    - Washington Support Office Organizational Development, Citizen Participation Program, 1980 (Box-folder 75/8)
    - Washington Support Office, Staff Groups, Citizen Participation, 1980 (Box-folder 75/9)
    - Work Plan and Revisions and Notes, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 75/10-11)
  - Subject Files, 1976-1982; Subseries 2; 1.25 linear ft.
    - Bott Collaborative Model, 1979 (Box-folder 76/1)
    - Bott's Collaborative Model, 1978 (Box-folder 76/2)
    - Citizen Participation Brochure for the Public, Patten-Hender Committee, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 76/3)
    - Citizen Participation in the American Federal System, 1979 (Box-folder 76/4)
    - Citizen Participation Training Materials, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 76/5)
    - Citizen's Organization Assessment Conference, 1979 (Box-folder 76/6)
    - Cosmos Club, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 76/7)
    - Cultural Resources, Citizen Participation, Civil War Round Table, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 76/8)
    - Departments of Agriculture and Interior, Citizen Participation Coordinator Tony Staed, 1980 (Box-folder 76/9)
    - Robert L. Herbst, 1977 (Box-folder 76/10)
    - Historical Preservation, 1980 (Box-folder 76/11)
    - Letter to Herbst, 1980 (Box-folder 77/1)
    - Mid-Atlantic Region, 1980 (Box-folder 77/2)
    - National Institute of Public Affairs, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 77/3)
    - National Park System Citizen's Guide, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 77/4)
    - Natural Resources Defense Council Retreat, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 77/5)
    - Order of the Indian Wars, 1980 (Box-folder 77/6)
    - Reference List on Current Biologue Information, 1978 (Box-folder 77/7)
    - Speech, Religion and Environmental Conference, 1980 (Box-folder 77/8)
    - Toward A More Responsive Government: A Training Program, 1978 (Box-folder 77/9)
    - Unity Meeting, 1980 (Box-folder 77/10-11)
    - Unity Meetings, Notes and Memos, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 77/12)
    - Urban Environment Foundation, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 77/13)
    - Whalen-Harper's Ferry Assessment and Direction Session, National Park Service, 1979 (Box-folder 78/1)
    - White House Survey of Public Participation Activities, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 78/2-4)
- National Leadership Development Conference Series, 1981-1988; Series VII; 5.25 linear ft.
  This series contains information regarding the development and implementation of the Conference Series including planning notes, memos, and correspondence, preliminary work plans, budgets, and evaluations.
  - Administration, 1981-1986; Subseries 1; 5.0 linear ft
    - Billing and Payments, Central Atlantic Region, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 78/5)
    - Billing, Rocky Mountain Conference, 1982 (Box-folder 78/6)
    - Central Atlantic Environmental Leadership Conference Planning Committee Materials, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 78/7)
    - Central Atlantic Environmental Leadership Conference, Planning Committee Members, 1983 (Box-folder 78/8)
    - Central Atlantic Environmental Leadership Conference, Program Plans, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 78/9-10)
    - Central Atlantic Region Coordinator's Expense Records, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 79/1)
    - Central Atlantic Regional Leadership Conference, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 79/2)
    - Central Atlantic Regional Leadership Conference, Timeline Schedule, 1986 (Box-folder 79/3)
    - Conference Coordinator Guide Materials, 1983 (Box-folder 79/4)
    - Conference Guide Materials, 1983 (Box-folder 79/5-6)
    - Conference on International Green Movements, 1986 (Box-folder 79/7)
    - Consequences of Nuclear War Conferences, 1983 (Box-folder 79/8-9)
    - Denver Rocky Mountain Regional Conference, 1982 (Box-folder 79/10)
    - Environmental Conference Information, Notes, Participants, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 80/1)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference Background, 1983 (Box-folder 80/2)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 80/3)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference Materials, Central Atlantic, Northwest, and Great Plains, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 80/4-6)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference Program Materials, January Conference, 1983 (Box-folder 80/7)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference Registrations, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 80/8-9)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference, April Invitation Lists, 1984 (Box-folder 81/1)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference, April Invitation Packets and Stationary, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 81/2)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference, April Program Materials, 1984 (Box-folder 81/3)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference, April Questionnaire, 1984 (Box-folder 81/4)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference, April Registrants, 1984 (Box-folder 81/5)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference, Invitation Lists, 1983 (Box-folder 81/6)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference, Resource Persons, 1984 (Box-folder 81/7)
    - Environmental Leadership Conference, Resources Persons, January Conference, 1983 (Box-folder 81/8)
    - Federal Executive Institute, Executive Development Days, Communication Practices, 1982 (Box-folder 81/9)
    - Great Plains Conference Planning, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 81/10)
    - Great Plains Environmental Leadership Conference, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 81/11-12)
    - Great Plains Leadership Conference, Regional Coordinators Billing and Payments, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 81/13)
    - Great Plains Leadership Conference Bills and Payments, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 82/1-3)
    - Great Plains Regional Conference, 1983 (Box-folder 82/4-5)
    - Groundwater Conference, 1985 (Box-folder 82/6-7)
    - National Audubon Society, Alaska Regional Conference, 1982 (Box-folder 82/8)
    - National Leadership Conference Notes, 1980 (Box-folder 82/9)
    - New England Conference Evaluation, 1982 (Box-folder 82/10)
    - New England Conference Evaluation Questionnaire, 1982 (Box-folder 82/11)
    - New England Conference Final Program Plans, 1982 (Box-folder 82/12)
    - New England Conference Follow-up Letter and Questionnaires, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 82/13)
    - New England Conference Media, 1982 (Box-folder 82/14)
    - New England Conferences, Bills and Payments, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 83/1-2)
    - New England Environmental Leadership Conference, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 83/3-4)
    - New England Regional Conference Program, 1982 (Box-folder 83/5)
    - New England Regional Conference Report, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 83/6)
    - New York-New Jersey Conference Evaluations, 1982 (Box-folder 83/7)
    - New York-New Jersey Conference Planning, 1982 (Box-folder 83/8)
    - New York-New Jersey Environmental Leadership Conference, 1982 (Box-folder 84/1-2)
    - New York-New Jersey Environmental Leadership Conference Evaluations, 1982 (Box-folder 84/3)
    - New York-New Jersey, Invoices and Bills, 1982 (Box-folder 84/4)
    - Northwest Conference Biographical Sketches, 1982 (Box-folder 84/5)
    - Northwest Conference Check Lists, Plans at Conference, 1982 (Box-folder 84/6)
    - Northwest Conference Evaluation and Questionnaire Analysis, 1982 (Box-folder 84/7)
    - Northwest Conference Evaluation Forms, Covering Letter, 1982 (Box-folder 84/8)
    - Northwest Conference Evaluation Forms, Covering Letter, 1982 (Box-folder 84/9)
    - Northwest Conference Evaluation Responses, 1982 (Box-folder 84/10-11)
    - Northwest Conference Invitations and Registration, 1982 (Box-folder 84/12)
    - Northwest Conference Prospectus, Proposed Agenda, Program Outline, 1981 (Box-folder 84/13)
    - Northwest Environmental Leadership Conference, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 85/1-2)
    - Northwest Regional Conference Prospectus, Agenda for Planning Committee, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 85/3)
    - Northwest Regional Conference, January Planning Meeting, 1982 (Box-folder 85/4)
    - Northwest Regional Conference, NAS, 1981 (Box-folder 85/5)
    - Northwest Regional Conference, Portland December Planning Meeting, 1981 (Box-folder 85/6)
    - Northwest Regional Conference, Preliminary Work Plan and Budget, 1981 (Box-folder 85/7)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference Agenda, Program Plan, 1982 (Box-folder 85/8)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference Directory, Listing of Attendants, 1983 (Box-folder 85/9)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference, Media, 1982 (Box-folder 85/10)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference, Program, Speakers, Agenda, Invitations, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 85/11)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference, Stewart M. Brandborg Notes and Minutes, 1981 (Box-folder 85/12-13)
    - Pacific Northwest Regional Conference Planning, Portland December Meeting, 1981 (Box-folder 86/1)
    - Regional Conference Conceptual Plan, Preliminary Work Plan and Budget, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 86/2)
    - Rocky Mountain Conference Follow-up Evaluation and State Conference Planning, 1982 (Box-folder 86/3)
    - South Central Regional Environmental Leadership Conference, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 86/4)
    - South Central Regional Leaders' Conference, 1984 (Box-folder 86/5)
    - South Central Regional Leadership Conference, 1984 (Box-folder 86/6)
    - Southeastern Conference, Billing, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 86/7)
    - Southeastern Conference, Program Planning, 1983 (Box-folder 86/8)
    - Southeastern Regional Conference Planning, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 86/9)
    - Southeastern Regional Environmental Leadership Conference, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 86/10-11)
    - Southwest Environmental Leadership Conference, 1986 (Box-folder 86/12-13)
    - Southwest Leaders Conference, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 87/1)
    - Southwest Virginia Working Conference, 1981 (Box-folder 87/2)
    - Southwest Virginia Working Conference, Environmental Task Force, 1981 (Box-folder 87/3)
    - Upper Midwest Conference Report Materials, 1983 (Box-folder 87/4)
    - Upper Midwest Conference, Billing and Payments, 1983 (Box-folder 87/5-6)
    - Upper Midwest Leadership Conference, 1983 (Box-folder 87/7-8)
    - Upper Midwest Region, Great Lakes Names, Planning Committee, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 88/1)
  - Subject Files, 1981-1988; Subseries 2; 0.5 linear ft.
    - Alaska Timber Pact, 1986 (Box-folder 88/2)
    - American Society for Training and Development, 1983 (Box-folder 88/3)
    - Brotherhood of Venery, 1985 (Box-folder 88/4)
    - Carrying Capacity, 1982 (Box-folder 88/5)
    - Center for Holistic Resource Management, 1985 (Box-folder 88/6)
    - College of the Atlantic Career Paths Workshop Final Report, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 88/7)
    - Components of the Environmental Worksheets, undated (Box-folder 88/8)
    - Creating Productive Relationships Workshop, 1984 (Box-folder 88/9-10)
    - Environmental Task Force, 1981 (Box-folder 88/11)
    - Friends of the Earth Team Building, 1983 (Box-folder 88/12)
    - Group of Ten Listing, 1985 (Box-folder 88/13)
    - Helpful Background Publications, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 88/14)
    - Leadership Development in Volunteer Organizations, 1982 (Box-folder 88/15)
    - National Audubon Society, Citizen Mobilization Campaign, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 88/16)
    - National Wildlife Federation, Conservation Directory, 1983 (Box-folder 88/17)
    - New England Current Work, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 89/1)
    - Newsletters and Reports, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 89/2)
    - Rocky Mountain Spotted Fever and the Nuttall's Cottontail, 1985 (Box-folder 89/3)
    - Rural Coalition, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 89/4)
    - Save Our Streams: A Citizen Action Program, 1984 (Box-folder 89/5)
    - Wild and Scenic Rogue River, 1982 (Box-folder 89/6)
    - Wilderness Society, "The Watt Book", 1981 (Box-folder 89/7-9)
- Friends of the Bitterroot and Wilderness Watch, 1984-2000; Series VIII; 0.5 linear ft.
  Subject files consisting of correspondence, plans, proposals, and notes.
  - Arizona Ecology-Justice Leadership Conference, 1991 (Box-folder 89/10)
  - Bitterroot National Forest Resource Monitoring, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 90/1)
  - Dedication to Sigurd Olson, The Wilderness Society, 1999 (Box-folder 90/2)
  - Friends of the Bitterroot Report, undated (Box-folder 90/3)
  - Montana Wilderness Association Publications, 1990 (Box-folder 90/4)
  - Montana Wilderness Association, Western Montana Leadership Conference, 1990 (Box-folder 90/5-6)
  - National Advanced Wilderness Management Training for Line Officers, 1995 (Box-folder 90/7-8)
  - Northern Rockies Ecosystem Protection Act, H.R. 1425, 1997 (Box-folder 90/9)
  - Sierra Club Grassroots Organizing Training Manual, 1999 (Box-folder 90/10)
  - Wilderness 2000 Conference (Box-folder 90/11-12)